Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Early Materials Collection AD.RG.001
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Early Materials Collection
2008-2010
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.001
1.5 Linear Feet in 1 legal-size document box, 1 half-document box, 1 oversize box, 1 oversize folder in flat file storage
Planning documents, publications, ephemera, promotional and commemorative materials related to the establishment and early years of NYU Abu Dhabi. This is an artificial collection of documents that were found in the University Archives and kept together. Duplicate copies of these records may exist in other NYU Abu Dhabi and/or NYU University Archives collections.
Administrative History
Established in partnership with New York University and the Emirate of Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, NYU Abu Dhabi is the first comprehensive liberal arts and science campus in the Middle East to be operated abroad by a major American research university. Founded upon "a shared understanding of the essential roles and challenges of higher education in the 21st century," the project was announced in 2007, and in 2010 NYU Abu Dhabi welcomed its inaugural class.
- "NYUAD At A Glance." https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/about/nyuad-at-a-glance/history.html
Scope and Contents
Early planning documents, publications, ephemera, and other promotional and commemorative materials produced and distributed on the occasion of the establishment of NYU Abu Dhabi, brought together into an artificial "early collection" by the archivist, as the provenance/donation information for these materials was not recorded.
This collection includes ephemeral items such as a copy of the first speech delivered to the Class of 2014 by then Dean of Students Jim Larrimore, early issues of the first iteration of an NYUAD student newspaper, "The Fishbowl," and ephemera from Candidate weekend. Also included is a small folder of architects' annotated meeting notes and printed records, including oversize copies of draft floor plan designs from June, July and August 2010. Of note is a specially designed commemorative book (published summer 2008), produced on the occasion of the establishment of NYU Abu Dhabi. Two volumes are published together into one book: "An Evolving Global Dynamic," and "A Partnership for the Future."(two copies).
Over time, as additional records have been transferred to the University Archives from various offices of leadership, many of the records and publications in this collection are also available and preserved in other Record Group collections, including the Hilary Ballon Papers; Records of the Office of Dean of Students; Records of the Office of Student Life, NYU Abu Dhabi Publications and Ephemera, and others.
This collection may be added to in the future, but most subsequent collections will be organized as part of the donating office.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Items in this collection were donated by a variety of individuals over a period of years, to capture the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi. Records of these donations have not been retained.
New York University Abu Dhabi; Architecture; Rafael Viñoly Architects
- Admissions Information Packet for NYU Abu Dhabi, 2009 (Box 1)
- Blank letterhead, NYU Abu Dhabi, ca. 2010 (Box 1)
- Commemorative Volumes: "An Evolving Global Dynamic"; "A Partnership for the Future", 2007-2008 (Oversize 1)
  New York University Abu Dhabi
- Concept Design Overview, Rafael Vinoly Architects, May 2010 (Box 1)
  Architecture; New York University Abu Dhabi
- Core Curriculum Planning Document: J-term 2011 Course Descriptions (Box 1)
- Document 1: The Vision for NYU Abu Dhabi, ca. 2008-2010 (Box 1)
- Downtown Campus: Laminated Parking Pass and NYUAD Office Email and Telephone Directory, ca. 2010 (Box 1)
- Global Education Quick Facts, September 2010 (Box 1)
- Iftar invitation and Ramadan pilot trip schedule [NYU Abu Dhabi Institute], September 2009 (Box 1)
- Maps: Visitor's Guide to Abu Dhabi; early Saadiyat Campus access road maps, 2009 (Box 1)
- Marhaba Autographed Program, 2010 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  This program, from the first Marhaba event held in 2010, is autographed by many who led specific sections of the event as well as those who were in attendance and participated.
- Marhaba Commemorative Photobook, 2010 (Oversize 1)
- Ma'a Salama and Commencement Memorabilia, 2014 (Box 1)
- Newspaper Announcements about NYU Abu Dhabi: Washington Square News, The National, 2009 (Map-case 1.c)
- Office Movement Plan from Regus Al Bateen to Downtown Campus, as of September 17, 2009; annotated with handwritten update on [November 18, 2009] (Box 1)
- Office of HR, Relocation and Transition Services: NYUAD School Kit, ca. 2010 (Box 1)
- Orientation and Planning, 2009: Guide to Living and Working in Abu Dhabi, 2010 (Box 1)
- Posters, Campus Activities and Events, ca. 2012-2013 (Box 1)
- Public Safety Tips, ca. 2010 (Box 1)
- Rudin Center for Transportation Policy and Management (and NYUAD): Strategic Issues Facing the Ports of New York and Dubai, October 2009 (Box 1)
- Space Planning, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
- Space Planning: architectural draft floor plan designs, June - August 2010 (oversize) (Map-case 1.c)
- Students: First Speech to Class of 2014, [Dean of Students] Jim Larrimore (Box 1)
- Students: "NYUAD Times," Issues 1 and 2, ca. 2010 (Box 1)
- Students: "The Fishbowl Tribune," Issues 1, 4, 5, 6, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
- Welcome to Sama Tower, August, 2010 (Box 1)
- Artifacts: Various (Box 2)
  Includes candidate weekend packets, t-shirts, souvenirs, giveaways